Marco Zanini

277 Ave. de la Division Leclerc

(0033) 67 385 3109

Chatenay-Malabry, 92290, France

chetto87@gmail.com

September 2006 - March 2010

Grade: 91/110

GitHub: mzanini

Innovative and involved software engineer with over three years of experience. Recognized high potential via bi-annual reviews. Fast and avid learner. Brought alternative and novel solutions to slowing projects. Perfectionist, takes pleasure in creating simple and beautiful information products, master in the art of code simplification. Excels in diverse and multicultural environments. Actively seeking new challenges.

Experience

	Experience			
So	oftware Engineer, Schlumberger	February 2013 - Present		
Paris region, France				
-	Integral part of a five person team developing communication software for operating Schlumberger's pressure and sampling tools. Implements UI-based workflow for testing and maintaining Schlumberger's logging tools.	C++/Boost, TDD, C#, WPF, TFS, Visual Studio		
-	Converted Matlab processing library to C++, removing the need for purchasing Matlab licenses and halving execution time.	C++, Matlab, Armadillo		
-	Scrum Master of a five person team. Led a 15 person team in adopting new technical practices resulting in improved code quality and efficiency. Increased unit test coverage by 50% on single components.	Agile methodologies, Scrum, Extreme programming, TDD		
-	Delivered first version of mobile monitoring system for well testing equipment, developing all phases of the project life cycle. Constructed back-end and frontend software: Web Service and an Android application. Predicted savings up to \$5,000/job via workload reduction and safety improvement.	impact analysis, Android, Java, C#,		
Researcher, The Irish Software Engineering Research Center (LERO) Limerick, Ireland October, 2011 – March, 2012		October, 2011 – March, 2012		
-	Developed adaptive system to enhance security in cloud computing environments, using federated identity management and SaaS cloud computing	Java, Cloud Computing, Google Apps for Business, Shibboleth		

Education

Master of Science, Computer EngineeringMarch 2010 – December 2012Polytechnic University of MilanGrade: 109/110

services like Google Apps for Business. Project presented at IBM, Dublin.

"Dingo": developed software capable of installing and running programs on clusters of machines, keeping them synchronized via file transferring through SSH.
 Shared on GitHub: https://github.com/mzanini/dingo

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering Polytechnic University of Milan

Thesis: "Analysis and benchmarking of high level synthesis applications". VHDL, C

- "DOSE Project": team development of an online multi-player game in collaboration with students from Ukraine and Switzerland. The project was launched by ETH Zurich.

Interests

Self Improvement	Getting Things Done, The Pomodoro Technique, Mindfulness meditation		
Running, Swimming, Rock Climbing	Peak half marathon: 1h 40min		
Web Development	Ruby on Rails: https://github.com/mzanini/sample_app		
Nationality	Language Proficiency		
Italian	Italian: Native English: Full professional French: Full professional		